Guilde to The Vinland Map and the Tartar Relation: Proofs and Research Files
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
The Vinland Map and the Tartar Relation: proofs and subject files
1964-1966
GEN MSS 1319
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
6
9 boxes + 1 broadside
The Vinland Map and the Tartar Relation: Proofs and Subject Files contains corrected and uncorrected proofs of this work on the "Vinland Map" (Beinecke MS 350A), as wells as extensive files of newspaper and magazine cliippings of book reviews, news items, and publicity about the map and the claims for its preColumbian origin.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Files retained by the library after the publication of The Vinland Map and the Tartar Relation by Yale University Press.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Scope and Contents
The Vinland Map and the Tartar Relation: Proofs and Subject Files contains corrected and uncorrected proofs of this work on the "Vinland Map" (Beinecke MS 350A), as wells as extensive files of newspaper and magazine cliippings of book reviews, news items, and publicity about the map and the claims for its preColumbian origin.
Arrangement
Organized into three groups: I. Proofs and proof sheets, 1964-1965; II. Subject Files, 1964-1966. III. Related Material, undated.
Vinland map; Early maps
- Proofs, 1964-1965; Series I; 2; (2 boxes)
  - Galley proofs, 1964-1965 (Box 1)
  - Page proofs, 1965 (Box 2)
- Subject files, 1965-1966; Series II; 2.75; (5 boxes)
  - Newspaper and magazine clippings, 1965-1966 (Box 3)
  - Newspaper and magazine clippings, 1965-1966 (Box 4)
  - Newspapers and magazines, 1965-1966 (Box 5)
  - Newspapers and magazines, 1965-1966 (Box 6)
  - Newspapers and magazines, 1965-1966 (Box 7)
- Publicity Material
  - Posters, undated (Box 8)
  - Posters, undated (Box 9)
  - Oversize publicity material, undated (Box 10)